What problems does material design try to solve?
Material Design 想要解决什么问题呢？
>> Well, the question of how a user goes between all these
用户如何在不同的设备之间转换
different devices is a key one.
这是个很关键的问题
And to the user, it's really just they're doing this one task.
对用户来说 他们在意的就是完成这一个任务
They're trying to do this one thing and it doesn't matter so
他们想要完成一个任务 对他们来说
much to them whether it happens to be on the phone in their pocket, or
是在手机上
the laptop that's on their desk.
还是笔记本上完成都没太大关系
So we want that kind of continuity.
所以我们想解决这个连续性问题
Something else we really focus on is motion.
另外我们还非常注重动态
We've seen all too often that motion is something that just kind of gets
我们经常会看到 动态图片
tacked on at the end.
一般是最后才补上的
So you do all this other work, and then you just kind of add in some animations.
也就是我们先做其他工作 最后才加入动画
>> After effect or something like that.
后期特效或者之类的
>> It is literally that, right?
对的 差不多这个意思
It's all done, so throw that thing in there.
其他都完成了 然后把这个东西丢进来吧
We try to think about motion from the very start, because we think that
但我们想要从一开始就考虑动态效果
kind of knowing how things are going to move around is so
因为我们觉得 如果一开始就知道东西是怎么移动的
powerful for giving feedback to the user about what they're doing.
我们能够让用户知道他们在做什么
So, you want to kind of plan for that in advance.
所以你就需要提前制定计划
And we try to have these materials that give the material design it's name.
所以我们用各种材料 这也是 Material Design 的名字来源
Or things like kind of paper and
或者类似的纸和墨
ink that can kind of move in predictable ways that feel tactile and
能够预先设计出用户觉得触碰性强觉得熟悉的动态形式
feel familiar to the user, but aren't bound by kind of boring old reality.
但不会拘泥于无聊的过时的一些做法
It can do kind of these really interesting things that makes
能够实现一些很有趣的东西
the user feel powerful,
让用户觉得产品很强大
and that's a key goal towards giving them a satisfying experience.
这是让用户有一个满意体验的关键所在
>> So the inspiration comes from design and material,
所以灵感是来源于设计和材料
actual material getting to play with.
真正地运用起来的材料
>> Yeah, I mean we really wanted to look at
是的 我们想要设计一些
things that felt familiar to the user.
用户觉得熟悉的东西
And we engage with those materials every day.
我们每天使用的这些材料
We don't engage with, kind of, these pieces of inscrutable glass.
不是说这些神秘的玻璃
>> That's right.
是的
>> In our day to day lives except when we're using these devices.
除了使用设备时 我们日常生活中使用的材料
So why should that be the metaphor?
所以为什么要用隐喻呢？
Let's go for something that's a little bit more predictable.
让我们用一些更容易猜想的东西
>> So where do I as an entrepreneur come to learn more about the material design?
所以作为一个企业家 我要在哪里学习更多的关于 Material Design 的东西呢？
>> The best place to start is just Google.com/design.
一开始最好就是去 Google.com/design
So from that site, we have a full specification,
在这个网站上 你会看到描述 Material Design 的
a set of guidelines that describes material design.
所有的规范以及一系列的指南
It breaks down the philosophy behind it, gives you some key principles to employ.
它会说明背后的一些思想 以及使用的关键原则
It's richly illustrated with imagery, with motion,
还有丰富的说明解释 包括图片、动态
samples of video, and also has a lot of resources that you can download.
视频样本 还有很多你可以下载的资源
So fonts, color palettes, sticker sheets of kind of common components for
包括字体、调色板、贴片集
all of the typical design tools that you might use.
和所有的你可能使用的日常设计工具的部件
>> So I can use those out of the box, and not reinvent the wheel, right?
所以我可以现成地使用这些东西 不需要重复制作 对吧？
>> Exactly, and then it should be very close to what you're getting on
就是这样 基本上可以直接运用在平台上
the platforms that directly support material.
直接支持你的材料